Guide to the Montana postcard collection 1893-2008, bulk 1905-1950
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Montana postcard collection
1893-2008, bulk 1905-1950
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Photograph Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-4739 photoarchives@mt.gov
PC 001
Montana Historical Society
21 boxes
Approximately 7750 postcards
The Montana postcard collection consists of approximately 7,750 commercially produced postcards primarily associated with Montana subjects. Postcards include photomechanical reproductions of artwork, greeting cards, geographic locations in Montana, and other subjects related to Montana and the West.
Historical Note
A postcard or post card is a rectangular piece of thick paper or thin cardboard intended for writing and mailing without an envelope and at a lower rate than a letter. The term Postcard refers to cards which were privately produced and were not sold with postage prepaid. Postcards are visual representations of people and places specific to a particular time, providing a record of changes in geography, graphic and artwork styles, social interests, and social concerns.
Deltiology, or postcard collecting, has been a popular hobby since the late nineteenth century. Germany's Heinrich von Stephan invented the concept of the postal card in 1865, and by 1870 postcards were being privately produced in the United States. The issuance of commemorative postcards at Chicago's World Columbian Exhibition (1893) followed by an act of Congress that allowed cards created by private publishers to be mailed at the same rate as government cards (1898) caused an increase in the production and collection of postcards in the United States.
The deltiology community generally divides the production of postcards in the United States into a few distinct eras. Postcards produced in the Pioneer Era (pre-1898) typically contained advertisements and appeared in urban centers in the East. Private Mailing Card Era (1898-Dec. 24, 1901) postcards had undivided backs and a Private Mailing Card logo. During the Undivided Back Postcard Era (Dec. 24, 1901-March 1, 1907), postcards had an undivided back and a Post Card logo. The Divided Back Era (March 1, 1907-1915), also known as the Golden Age of postcards, featured postcards with space on the verso for both an address and a message. Previously, only the address of the recipient was allowed on the verso. This period marks the apex of the popularity of mailing postcards. World War I, influenza epidemics, and the advent of the telephone caused the decline of the postcard after 1915. During the White Border Era (1915-1930), postcards were often produced with white borders around the screened image. The Linen Card Era (1930-1945) reflects a shift in production towards printing on linen card stock, which gave postcards a textured look and feel. Finally, during the Photochrome Era (1945-present), glossy color postcards became favored.
Until the mid-1970s, most cards produced in the United States were the "standard" size, approximately 3-1/2 x 5 inches. The "continental" size, approximately 4 x 6 inches, was a size that was common in Europe earlier than in the United States, but most of the cards sold in the U.S. since the mid-1970s are this size. Super-sized postcards approximately 5 x 7 inches were published more recently.
The printing on color lithograph postcards varies in quality. Most view cards are based on black-and-white photographs with color added. The printing on these cards often has good detail and deep colors. Greeting cards also are colorful and usually embossed, although sometimes the graphics on these cards can be of poor quality.
The Montana postcard collection consists of approximately 7,750 commercially produced postcards primarily associated with Montana subjects. Postcards in the collection were produced between 1893 and 2005, with most of the postcards dating between 1905 and 1950. The collection includes four series: the Artwork Series, the Greetings Series, the Subject Series, and the Oversized Postcards Series. The collection consists of photomechanical postcards and does not contain photographic or real photo postcards.
The Artwork Series contains reproductions of artwork, including paintings, sketches, etchings, sculpture, and woodcarving. Topically, the artwork focuses on Montana and the West. Over half of the series reproduces the work of Charles Marion Russell.
The Greetings Series comprises postcards sent in honor of a life event, such as a holiday or birthday, to establish general contact with an acquaintance or loved one, or to express a sentiment, like congratulations or humor.
The largest series, the Subject Series, contains postcards of geographic locations in Montana and subjects related to Montana and the West, often sold as souvenirs to tourists visiting locations in the state. The series primarily contains images of Montana cities and towns, state and national parks, bodies of water, mountains, and other geographic locations. The series also contains reproductions of L. A. (Laton Alton) Huffman photographs on Montana subjects.
Photographer L. A. Huffman settled in Montana Territory around 1879 to work as the Post Photographer at Fort Keogh. Huffman ran a photographic studio in Miles City from the early 1880s to 1890. In 1905 he began selling prints made from his negatives of frontier life in Montana. Huffman produced some of his images on postcard mounts, notably in two major sets. The 1907 Huffman set consists of twenty-seven black and white postcards, with some color variants. The 1926 Huffman set contains fifteen black and white postcards printed with a white border. The L. A. Huffman postcards in the Subject Series include cards from the 1907 and 1926 sets and later color reproductions of Huffman images.
The Oversized Postcards Series consists of postcards measuring greater than 4 x 6 inches.
Many of the postcards in this collection are attributed to specific photographers, photographic studios, or publishing companies. Creator information is not included on this finding aid.
The postcards are arranged in series according to topic. The Artwork Series contains postcards with reproductions of artwork and is arranged alphabetically by the artists' surname. The Greetings Series comprises postcards sent in honor of a life event, such as a holiday or birthday, or to establish general contact with an acquaintance or loved one. The Greetings Series is arranged alphabetically by type of greeting. The Subject Series contains postcards of geographic locations in Montana and subjects related to Montana and the West, arranged alphabetically by topic. Sub-topics within the subject series are arranged alphabetically by topic, with the exception of Yellowstone National Park, which is arranged alphabetically by publisher. The Oversized Postcards series, containing postcards measuring greater than 4 x 6 inches, is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request.
Printed inventory available in Photograph Archives reference room.
Fappel, L. Postcard types and eras. Accessed December 23, 2010. http://www.postcardy.com/types.html.
Klamkin, Marian, Picture Postcards (New York, Dodd, Mead and Company, 1974).
Kollodge, Jack, Custer Battlefield, Twin City Postcard Club 10 (1986): 3.
Seneca County (N.Y.) A History of Postcards. Accessed December 11, 2010. http://www.co.seneca.ny.us/history/Postcards%20History.pdf.
This collection is indexed under the following headings. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Huffman, L. A. (Laton Alton), 1854-1931.
Russell, Charles M. (Charles Marion), 1864-1926.
Montana.
Billings (Mont.)
Butte (Mont.)
Glacier National Park (Mont.)
Great Falls (Mont.)
Helena (Mont.)
Missoula (Mont.)
Virginia City (Mont.)
Yellowstone National Park.
Animals.
Art.
Holidays.
Indians of North America.
Lakes.
Mines and mineral resources.
Mountains.
Postcards.
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Artwork, 1904-2008; Series I
  - Auth, Robert -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Beaulaurier, Leo -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Blake, Morris -- Woodcarvings (Box 1)
  - Brown, Art -- Pen and Ink sketches (Box 1)
  - Cross, Henry H., 1837-1918 -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Curtiss, Maureen -- Drawings (Box 1)
  - Drake-Robinson, Leslie -- Artwork (Box 1)
  - Fell, Olive -- Etchings (Box 1)
  - Gollings, Elling William, 1878-1932 -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Griffen, R. -- Drawings (Box 1)
  - Hall, Bob -- Sketches (Box 1)
  - Harrison, Robert -- Sculptures (Box 1)
  - Innes, John -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Jacobson, Dan -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Lochrie, Elizabeth. -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - McCarty, Lea -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - McCollum, Ernest, 1886-1952. -- Drawings (Box 1)
  - Nimy, Buck -- Etchings (Box 1)
  - Nixon, Sharon -- Sketches (Box 1)
  - Paxson, E. S., 1852-1919. -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Peterson, L. -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Racine, Al -- Etchings (Box 1)
  - Ralston, J. K., 1896- -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Reed, Rae Anne -- Artwork (Box 1)
  - Reedstrom, Ernest Lisle -- Sketches (Box 1)
  - Reiss, Winold, 1886-1953. -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909 -- Artwork (Box 1)
  - Russell, Charles M. (Charles Marion), 1864-1926 -- Artwork (Box 1)
  - Sawyer, Mary -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Schreyvogel, Charles, 1861-1912 -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Segesman, John -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Seltzer, O. C. (Olaf C.), 1877-1957 -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Shinners, Will. -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Standing Soldier, Andrew -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Standing, William. -- Sketches (Box 1)
  - Walking, Felix -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Weaver, J. B. -- Sketches (Box 1)
  - Wimar, Carl, 1828-1862 -- Paintings (Box 1)
  - Wolfe, Byron -- Paintings (Box 1)
- Greetings, ca. 1900-2007; Series II
  - Advertising (Box 2)
  - Animals (Box 2)
    - Cats
    - Dogs
    - General
  - Baseball (Box 2)
  - Best Wishes (Box 2)
    - Animals
    - Floral
    - Landscapes
    - Luck
    - People
  - Birth Announcements and Baby Greetings (Box 2)
  - Birthday (Box 2)
    - Animals
    - Floral
  - Birthday (Box 3)
    - Landscapes
    - People
    - Verse
  - Children (Box 3)
    - Dutch
    - General
  - Christmas (Box 3)
    - Adults
    - Angels
    - Bells
    - Birds
    - Cats
    - Children
    - Nativity
    - Santa Claus
  - Christmas (Box 4)
    - Verse
    - General
  - Congratulations (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Easter (Box 4)
    - Angels
    - Chicks and Hens
    - Crosses
  - Easter (Box 5)
    - Eggs
    - Jesus
    - People
    - Rabbits
    - Sheep
    - General
  - Floral (Box 5)
    - Floral set
    - Roses
    - General (by color)
  - Fourth of July (Box 5)
  - Friendship (Box 5)
  - Good Luck (Box 5)
  - Greetings and Regards (Box 5)
  - Greetings From ____ (Box 6)
    - Greetings From Montana Places
    - Pennant
    - General
  - Halloween (Box 6)
  - Humorous (Box 6)
    - Children
    - Military
    - Presidents
    - Romance and Sexuality
    - General
  - Leap Year (Box 6)
  - Leather (Box 6)
  - Literary (Box 6)
  - Marriage (Box 6)
  - Memorial Day (Box 6)
  - Mother's Day (Box 6)
  - Mourning (Box 6)
  - Names (Box 6)
  - New Year's Day (Box 7)
    - Angels
    - Animals
    - Birds
    - Clocks and Time
    - Flora and Foliage
    - Landscapes
    - Nautical
    - People
  - Patriotic (Box 7)
  - Presidents (Box 7)
  - Religious (Box 7)
  - Remembrance (Box 7)
  - Romance (Box 7)
    - Cupid
    - Kisses
    - Tokens and Verse
    - General
  - Scenes and Scenery (Box 7)
  - St. Patrick's Day (Box 8)
  - Tall Tale (Box 8)
  - Thanksgiving (Box 8)
    - Children
    - Pilgrims
    - Turkey
    - Vegetables and Menus
  - Valentine's Day (Box 8)
    - Animals
    - Children
    - Couples
    - Cupid
    - Floral
    - Verse
    - Women
  - Women (Box 8)
- Subject, 1893-1996; Series III
  - Absaroka Range (Box 9)
  - Airplanes (Box 9)
  - Alder Gulch (Box 9)
  - Alhambra Hot Springs (Box 9)
  - Anaconda (Mont.) (Box 9)
    - Buildings
    - Smelter
    - Streets
    - Views
  - Anchor Lake (Box 9)
  - Avon (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Badlands (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Badlands (N.D.) (Box 9)
  - Baker (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Bannack (Mont.) (Box 9)
    - Buildings
    - Mines and mining
    - Streets
    - Views
  - Basin (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Basin Creek Reservoir (Box 9)
  - Bear Paw Mountains (Box 9)
  - Bears (Box 9)
  - Beartooth Mountains (Box 9)
  - Beaverhead River and Beaverhead Rock (Box 9)
  - Belgrade (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Belt (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Belt Mountains (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Bicycles (Box 9)
  - Big Elk Ranch (Box 9)
  - Big Fork (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Big Hole National Battlefield (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Big Hole Dam (Box 9)
  - Big Hole River (Mont.) and Big Hole River Valley (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Bighorn Mountains (Wyo. and Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Big Sandy (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Big Sky (Mont.) (Box 9)
  - Big Sky Magic Enterprises [historical series] (Box 9)
  - Billings (Mont.) (Box 9)
    - Buildings
  - Billings (Mont.) (Box 10)
    - Streets
    - Surrounding Area
    - Views
  - Birds (Box 10)
  - Bison, American (Box 10)
    - Big Medicine
  - Bitterroot Range (Idaho and Mont.), Bitterroot River (Mont.), and Bitterroot River Valley (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Blackfoot River (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Bob Marshall Wilderness (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Bonner (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Boulder Hot Springs (Box 10)
  - Boulder (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Bozeman (Mont.) (Box 10)
    - Buildings
    - Ladies' Imperial Band
    - Montana State University
    - Streets
    - Views
  - Bridger (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Bridger Canyon (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Broadus (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Browne's Lake (Box 10)
  - Browning (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Burnt Fork Lake (Box 10)
  - Bridger (Mont.) (Box 10)
  - Butte (Mont.) (Box 10)
    - Buildings
    - Columbia Gardens
  - Butte (Mont.) (Box 11)
    - Mines and Mining
    - Streets
    - Views
  - Camas Hot Springs (Box 11)
  - Canoes and canoeing (Box 11)
  - Canyon Ferry Dam (Mont.) and Canyon Ferry Lake (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Carlton Creek (Box 11)
  - Carts and wagons (Box 11)
  - Cattle (Box 11)
  - Cattle brands (Box 11)
  - Chateau de Mores State Historic Site (N.D.) (Box 11)
  - Chester (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Chico Hot Springs (Box 11)
  - Chinook (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Choteau (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Circle (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Clark Canyon Reservoir (Box 11)
  - Clark Fork (Mont. and Idaho) (Box 11)
  - Clinton (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Colstrip (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Columbia Falls (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Columbus (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Continental Divide (Box 11)
  - Cooke City (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Corvallis (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Corwin Springs (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Cowboys (Box 11)
  - Coyotes (Box 11)
  - Crazy Mountains (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Crystal Lake (Fergus County, Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Custer (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Deer (Box 11)
  - Deer Lodge (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Dewey (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Diamond City (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Dillon (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Drummond (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - Dude ranches (Box 11)
  - East Glacier Park (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - East Helena (Mont.) (Box 11)
  - East Rosebud Lake (Box 11)
  - Ekalaka (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Electric (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Elk (Box 12)
  - Elkhorn (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Elliston (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Ennis Lake (Box 12)
  - Essex (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Eureka (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fairs (Box 12)
    - Century of Progress International Exposition (1933-1934: Chicago, Ill.)
    - Expo '74 (Spokane, Wash.)
    - Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition (1905: Portland, Or.)
    - World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Ill.)
  - Farms and farming (Box 12)
  - Fish and fishing (Box 12)
  - Flags (Box 12)
  - Flathead Indian Reservation (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Flathead Lake (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Flathead River (B.C. and Mont.) and Flathead River Valley (B.C. and Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Flowers (Box 12)
    - Bitterroot
  - Forests and forest fires (Box 12)
  - Forsyth (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Assiniboine (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Benton (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Harrison (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Owen (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Peck Dam (Mont.) and Fort Peck Lake (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fort Union Trading Post National Historic Site (N.D. and Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Fraternal organizations (Box 12)
  - Freight and freightage (Box 12)
  - Freighting: A tribute to early American freighters series by Joseph M. Hartman (Box 12)
  - Gallatin Canyon (Mont.), Gallatin Range (Mont.), Gallatin River (Wyo. and Mont.), and Gallatin River Valley (Wyo. and Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Gardiner (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Garnet Range (Box 12)
  - Gates of the Mountains (Box 12)
  - Georgetown Lake (Mont.) (Box 12)
  - Giant Springs Heritage State Park (Box 12)
  - Glacier Creek (Box 12)
  - Glacier National Park (Mont.) (Box 13)
    - Camps and chalets
    - Chief Mountain
    - East Glacier Hotel
    - Flowers
    - Garden Wall
    - Glaciers
    - Going to the Sun Highway
    - Going to the Sun Mountain
    - Grinnell Mountain
    - Heavens Peak
    - Iceberg Lake
    - Lake Ellen Wilson
    - Lake Janet
    - Lake Josephine
    - Lake McDonald
    - Lake McDonald Hotel
    - Lakes - Miscellaneous
    - Little Chief Mountain
    - Logan Pass
    - Many Glacier Hotel
    - McDonald Creek
    - Mountain goats
    - Mountains - Miscellaneous
    - Piegan Pass
    - Reynolds Mountain
    - Rising Wolf Mountain
    - St. Mary Lake
  - Glacier National Park (Mont.) (Box 14)
    - Sunrift Gorge
    - Swiftcurrent Lake
    - Thunderbird Mountains
    - Trails
    - Two Medicine Lake
    - Viewbooks
    - Waterfalls
    - Waterton Lakes National Park border
  - Glasgow (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Glendive (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Granite Lake (Box 14)
  - Great Falls (Mont.) (Box 14)
    - Buildings
    - Falls and rivers
    - Parks
    - Smelter
    - Streets
    - Views
  - Gregson Hot Springs (Box 14)
  - Guns and rifles (Box 14)
  - Hamilton (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Happy Valley (Box 14)
  - Harlem (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Harlowtown (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Hauser Dam (Mont.) and Hauser Lake (Box 14)
  - Havre (Mont.) (Box 14)
  - Helena (Mont.) (Box 15)
    - Broadwater Hotel and Natatorium
    - Buildings
    - Carroll College
    - Dry Gulch
    - Fire Tower
    - Hangman's Tree
    - Last Chance Tour Train
    - Mines and Mining
    - Montana Historical Society
    - Montana State Capitol
  - Helena (Mont.) (Box 16)
    - Montana State Fair
    - Moose Creek
    - Mount Helena
    - Parks
    - Pioneers
    - Reeder's Alley
    - State Nursery
    - Streets
    - Viewbooks
    - Views
  - Hell Gate (Missoula County, Mont.) (Box 16)
  - Highways and interstates (Box 16)
  - Hobson (Mont.) (Box 16)
  - Holter Dam (Mont.) (Box 16)
  - Holland Lake (Mont.) (Box 16)
  - Horses (Box 16)
  - Huffman, L. A. (Laton Alton), 1854-1931 (Box 16)
    This series contains reproductions of L.A. (Laton Alton) Huffman photographs on Montana subjects. It contains two sets: 1907 set consists of black and white postcards with color variants and 1926 set consists of black and white postcards with a white border.
  - Hungry Horse Dam (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Hunters Hot Springs (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Hunting (Box 17)
  - Huntley (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Indian Head (peak) (Box 17)
  - Indians (Box 17)
    - Blackfeet
    - Crow
    - Dakota
    - Flathead
    - Kootenai
    - Nez Perce
    - Indians of North America
  - Ingomar (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Joliet (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Kalispell (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Kendall (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Kibbey Canyon (Box 17)
  - Kootenai Falls and Kootenai River (Box 17)
  - Lake Como (Box 17)
  - Lewis and Clark Caverns State Park (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail (Box 17)
  - Lewistown (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Libby (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Lima Dam (Box 17)
  - Little Bighorn Battlefield National Monument (Mont.) (Box 17)
    - Coffeen-Schnitger Trading Company set
    - General
  - Livingston (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Lolo Hot Springs (Box 17)
  - Lolo Indian Trail (Box 17)
  - Lombard (Mont.) (Box 17)
  - Lost Trail Hot Springs (Box 17)
  - Lost Trail Pass (Box 18)
  - Lumber industry (Box 18)
  - MacDonald Pass (Box 18)
  - Madison River (Box 18)
  - Madison River Power Dam (Box 18)
  - Makoshika State Park (Box 18)
  - Malta (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Marias River (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Marysville (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - McLeod (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Medicine Rocks State Park (Box 18)
  - Melville (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Miles City (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Mill Creek (Box 18)
  - Mines and mining (Box 18)
    - Dredges and dredging
    - Smelting
  - Mission Range (Box 18)
  - Missoula (Mont.) (Box 18)
    - Buildings
    - Floods
    - Fort Missoula
    - Marshall Grade
    - Mount Jumbo
    - Parks
    - Rattlesnake Creek
    - Scenic drives
    - Streets
    - University of Montana
    - Views
  - Missouri River (Box 18)
  - Montana - General (Box 18)
  - Montana - Poems (Box 18)
  - Montana - Viewbooks (Box 18)
  - Moore (Mont.) (Box 18)
  - Moose (Box 18)
  - Mount Haggin (Box 18)
  - Mountain sheep (Box 18)
  - Mystic Lake (Box 18)
  - National Postcard Week (Box 19)
  - Neihart (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Nevada City (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Ninepipe National Wildlife Refuge (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Outhouses (Box 19)
  - Paradise Valley (Box 19)
  - People (Box 19)
    - Bonner, John W. (John Woodrow), 1902-1970
    - Bowen, Eli
    - Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925
    - Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917
    - Cameron, Evelyn, 1868-1928
    - Hickok, Wild Bill, 1837-1876
    - Judge, Thomas L.
    - Mullan, John
    - Pawnee Bill, 1860-1942
    - Russell, Charles M. (Charles Marion), 1864-1926
    - Sacagawea
    - Schwinden, Ted
    - Taylor, W. H.
  - Philipsburg (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Piedmont (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Pipestone Hot Springs (Box 19)
  - Plentywood (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Polson (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Pompeys Pillar (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Poplar (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Potomac Valley (Box 19)
  - Quake Lake (Box 19)
  - Radersburg (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Railroads (Box 19)
    - Burlington Northern Railway Company
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company
    - Freedom Train
    - Great Northern Railway Company
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company
    - Miscellaneous
  - Ravalli (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Red Lodge (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Red Mountain, Lewis Range (Box 19)
  - Richland (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Robbers' Roost (Box 19)
  - Rock Creek (Box 19)
  - Rock Creek Lake (Box 19)
  - Rodeos (Box 19)
  - Roundup (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Ryegate (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - St. Ignatius Mission (Lake County, Mont.) (Box 19)
  - St. Mary's Mission (Stevensville, Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Saint Regis (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Salmon Lake (Box 19)
  - Sawtooth Creek (Box 19)
  - Scapegoat Mountain (Box 19)
  - Seeley Lake (Box 19)
  - Sheep (Box 19)
  - Shelby (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Sheridan Butte (Box 19)
  - Sheridan (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Sidney (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Silver Gate (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Silver Lake (Box 19)
  - Sixteen Mile Canyon (Box 19)
  - Skalkaho Falls (Box 19)
  - Skis and skiing (Box 19)
  - Sluice Boxes State Park (Box 19)
  - Snakes (Box 19)
  - Somers (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Spanish Creek (Box 19)
  - Spanish Peaks (Box 19)
  - Stagecoach lines and Stagecoaches (Box 19)
  - Stanford (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Steamboats (Box 19)
  - Stevensville (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Stockett (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Sun River (Box 19)
  - Superior (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Swan Lake (Box 19)
  - Swan Range (Box 19)
  - Swan River (Box 19)
  - Taft (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Taylor Creek (Box 19)
  - Taylor Peak (Box 19)
  - Terry (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Thompson Falls (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Tin Cup Creek (Box 19)
  - Townsend (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Trees and shrubs (Box 19)
  - Troy (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Twin Bridges (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - Two Dot (Mont.) (Box 19)
  - United States. Army. (Box 19)
  - United States. Navy. (Box 19)
    - Montana (Armored cruiser)